Maddy: In this video we are going to
discuss how we can use customer feedback
to help improve an organisation.
Phillip: Customer feedback isn’t especially
useful when it’s just taken on its own.
For it to make sense and help your
organisation, you need to learn to be
able to interpret it and analyse it.
When you start making real sense of customer
feedback, you’ll have a powerful tool for
continual organisation and product improvement.
So, it’s important that you get this right.
Maddy: It’s best to start by grouping the
feedback into different categories, such
as customer service experience, website
experience, and product satisfaction.
By grouping feedback like this, it is easier
to see the patterns that will start to emerge,
such as does one category of feedback seem to
attract more negative comments than positive?
Phillip: You might also notice that customers
are happy with the product and their interactions
with customer service assistants, but are
not happy about the website experience.
This can help you as you might have assumed
that customers really liked the website because
you personally approved it, but the feedback is
telling you a different story and the website
is not as successful as the product or service.
Maddy: It’s also important to always be objective
when looking at feedback, so try to stick
to the facts and figures, rather than just
speculating without any evidence, or just basing
things on your opinions or of those around you.
The facts revealed by interpreting the
feedback are often a much more reliable
guide when it comes to improving how to do
things or making changes for the better.
Phillip: Try looking for common themes or repeated
statements in the feedback you’re receiving.
Remember if more than one person has had
the same issue, or negative experience
then this is a problem to be addressed,
so you can find out what’s going on.
Or maybe your attention is drawn to
positive experiences people have had, that
hadn’t been recognised before, such as
finding out about a new, important skill
that someone has, or an opportunity for
development and improvement is identified.
Maddy: The volume of feedback can also be an
important piece of information in its own right.
If you start receiving more feedback
across all the categories, either
negative or positive, this maybe an
indication that this needs your attention.
Ask yourself, has there been a
big change in how the team works?
Phillip: Was there a new marketing promotion?
Maddy: Has your core product changed?
Phillip: Likewise, if the amount of
feedback starts to reduce in any or all
areas, you should investigate what might
have caused that, and whether or not the
remaining feedback is positive or negative.
Maddy: Sometimes the most important
feedback to address won’t be noticeable
by its amount but will be more significant
due to its strategic importance.
Imagine if one or two users discover
that there’s a dramatically unsafe
feature in your main product.
Even though only a small number of people
may have noticed this, it may mean that
everyone with that product might now
be at risk, without even realising it.
This sort of feedback should be investigated
swiftly and often will involve a recall.
Phillip: Finally, feedback doesn’t
do anything to help you on its own,
even once you’ve interpreted it.
It is the actual concrete steps that you
take, to act on the feedback that you
receive, that changes things and the best
way to do this, is to form action plans
with your team and other key stakeholders.
Maddy: By structuring the action plan based
on objective facts derived from customer
feedback, you’re putting the customers’
insights to good use and improving your
organisation and future customer experiences.